Mario Martínez Lanuza



Economist & Software Engineer

My Contact

mmartinez@mvanalytic.com

linkedin.com/in/mmartinezl

www.mmartinezl.com

() +(506) 8896-9379

https://github.com/mariomartinez-proyecto1

Education

- Software engineer Universidad Cenfotec
- Economy Universidad de Costa Rica
- Risk Technician Universidad de Costa Rica
- Technical accounting Colegio Vocacional de Artes y Oficios de Cartago

Hard Skill

- Web applications
- Mobile apps
- Relational databases
- · Financial analysis of credit from companies and banks
- Financial Analysts Trainer
- Credit counselor

Soft Skill

- Teamwork
- Leadership
- Patience
- Persisntence
- Adaptability

About Me

I am an economist with an emphasis in finance with 24 years of experience in the area of financial analysis of large companies and banks; and I am an instructor for Financial Analysts. Furthermore, I am a Software Engineer with experience working in a team, developing web and mobile applications, as well as databases.

Work Experience

Sistema de Banca para el Desarrollo | Financial Consultant 2022 - present

As a founding consultant of MV Analytic, S.A. I provide consulting services in the area of credit, second-tier loans and guarantees for the placement of resources of the Development Banking System.

Sistema de Banca para el Desarrollo | Credit Director 2019

Create the structure of the Credit Department, its policies and regulations.

GyV, S.A | Financial Consultant

2013 - 2019

Financial consultant in the area of accreditation of financial Operators with the Development Banking System (Law 9274)

Banco Nacional de Costa Rica | Senior Financial Analyst 1998 - 2013

Senior Financial Analyst, performing functions of supervisor and instructor of Financial Analysts; In addition, in charge of the area of payment capacity of natural and legal persons, their policies and regulations.

References

Marco Flores Stoviak

Dirección de Políticas / Director Quanto Soluciones / CEO

+(506)8320-3144

mfloress@bncr.fi.cr

Alexander Ramírez González

+(506) 8998-5673

alexander.ramirez_g@quantosoluciones.com